<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LMS on LiaScript</title><link>/tags/lms/</link><description>Recent content in LMS on LiaScript</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/lms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OPAL Integrates LiaScript: A Milestone for Interactive Learning in German Higher Education</title><link>/blog/093_opal-integrates-liascript/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>/blog/093_opal-integrates-liascript/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to announce that OPAL (Online-Plattform für Akademisches Lehren und Lernen), the primary Learning Management System serving 21 Saxon universities with over 80,000 users and approximately 35,000 online courses, now natively supports LiaScript!</description></item><item><title>LiaScript Meets OPAL!</title><link>/blog/liascript-meets-opal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>/blog/liascript-meets-opal/</guid><description>LiaScript Dokumente im OPAL Lern-Management-System direkt hochladen? Dank der Zusammenarbeit von Technische Universität Chemnitz, der TU Bergakademie Freiberg, der BPS Bildungsportal Sachsen GmbH und der #LiaScript-Community ist dies nach dem jüngsten Update jetzt möglich.</description></item><item><title>Open Educational Ressources (OER) - Vision, Vorteile und praktische Umsetzung mit LiaScript und OPAL</title><link>/blog/oer-vision/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>/blog/oer-vision/</guid><description>Gemeinsam mit Studenten Lehrmaterialien erstellen und diese unter einer freien OER Lizenz teilen.</description></item><item><title>From Hero to Zero with Learning Management Systems</title><link>/blog/from-hero-to-zero-with-lms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>/blog/from-hero-to-zero-with-lms/</guid><description>Why and How LMSs fail in distributing knowledge Abstract: Learning Management Systems provide more restrictions than access to educational resources and developing courses with the offered authoring tools is more tedious and intimidating task than a creative one.</description></item></channel></rss>