<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on LiaScript</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on LiaScript</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://LiaScript.github.io/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>WorldMap</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/world-map/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/world-map/</guid><description>Since LiaScript is a distributed approach to create and share educational content, it is difficult to keep track of all the projects that are created with it. This is why we have created a world map that shows the locations of projects that have been implemented with LiaScript so far.
If you want to add your project or event to this map, please follow the instructions in the blog post:</description></item><item><title>Atom - Editor</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/atom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/atom/</guid><description>Although, the Atom editor is not actively maintained anymore, it is still a great editor for writing Markdown documents. Especially if your are dealing with very large documents, the Atom editor outperforms other editors like VS-Code. We still use the Atom editor for our documentation:
https://github.com/liascript/docs
Installation To install the Atom editor together with the LiaScript-Preview plugin, follow the instructions in the following blog post:
Install Atom with LiaScript (Deprecated) This blog entry presents a little workaround and shows how you can still use our two plugins to develop your LiaScript courses offline with the Atom editor.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Get in touch with us via &amp;hellip;
Gitter: https://app.gitter.im/#/room/#LiaScript_community:gitter.im Twitter: https://twitter.com/LiaScript GitHub: https://github.com/LiaScript Email: LiaScript@web.de YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/@liascript4180</description></item><item><title>Development - Server</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/development-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/development-server/</guid><description>If you want to use another of your preferred editors, you can also install the development server. By running it you can point it to any of your projects and it will deliver a preview the project for you in the browser.
Install You can directly download the latest version for your system from the assets:
https://github.com/LiaScript/LiaScript-DevServer/releases/
or install it via the NodeJS package manager npm &amp;hellip;
NodeJS If you haven&amp;rsquo;t installed it yet, you will have to install NodeJS for your system.</description></item><item><title>Exporter</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/exporter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/exporter/</guid><description>This shall be a generic LiaScript-Exporter that can export educational content into different formats, so that LiaScript courses can also be utilized in different Learning Management Systems (LMS) or Readers for static content (PDF, ePub, &amp;hellip;). At the moment there is only support for SCORM1.2, as the most wide-spread exchange format. See the last section LMS Support List
Example of uploading a LiaScript-course to
But, it is still the easiest way to share your courses via https://LiaScript.</description></item><item><title>Imprint</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/imprint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/imprint/</guid><description>Publisher Technische Universität Bergakademie Freiberg
Akademiestraße 6
09599 Freiberg, Germany
Phone: +49 3731 39-0
Fax: +49 3731 39-3323
Email: universitaet@tu-freiberg.de
Website: http://tu-freiberg.de
Legal Form and Representation Technische Universität Bergakademie Freiberg is a public corporation. It is legally represented by the current Rector, Prof. Dr. Klaus-Dieter Barbknecht.
Supervisory Authority Saxon State Ministry for Science and the Arts
Wigardstraße 17
01097 Dresden, Germany
VAT Identification Number
In accordance with § 27 a of the German VAT Act: DE 141136178</description></item><item><title>Live - Editor</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/live-editor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/live-editor/</guid><description>The LiveEditor is an entirely browser-based collaborative Editor. It covers nearly all functionalities of other server-based solutions, but in this case, you don&amp;rsquo;t need a server nor a login. All your notes or courses will be directly stored within your browser.
Try the LiveEditor In contrast to only image-uploads you can furthermore also upload audio and video files, as shown in the video below, and use any kind of LiaScript-template to add additional functionalities.</description></item><item><title>Newsletter Subscription</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/newsletter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/newsletter/</guid><description/></item><item><title>VSCode - Editor</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/vscode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/vscode/</guid><description>Installation To install VSCode with LiaScript follow the steps from the following Blog-post.
Install Visual Studio Code with LiaScript Due to some problems with package updates for Atom editor, we decided to created two LiaScript extensions for VSCode. However, Atom can still be used to create LiaScript courses and from our point of view it is still the easier editor to learn (for more information follow this link). But, it is now also possible to develop courses and preview them with Visual-Studio-Code.</description></item><item><title>VSCode-Web - Editor</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/vscode-web/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/vscode-web/</guid><description>This is a preview module for LiaScript courses developed for the VSCode-Web editor, thus no installation everything is browser-based. If you have a GitHub-account simply follow the steps in the video below to for installation:
Usage After installing press F1 to open the fuzzy search and type &amp;ldquo;liascript&amp;rdquo;, three options will be presented:
LiaScript: Toggle Preview [Alt L] - (on Mac [Cmd L])
This will open a panel on the right side (or close it).</description></item></channel></rss>