<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Books on LiaScript</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/tags/books/</link><description>Recent content in Books on LiaScript</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://LiaScript.github.io/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lua Programming</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/lua-programming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/lua-programming/</guid><description>This example is a port of the Lua programming course from the open wikibook Lua-Programming to LiaScript. It is a fully working Lua programming course, that can be used as a basis for your own course.
Start Course This example uses the Lua template which implements the Lua interpreter and VM from interpreter and VM https://daurnimator.github.io. The only that is required to make Lua code snippets executable in LiaScript is to attach the @LUA.</description></item><item><title>Fischbestimmer - FISHIDENTIFIER</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/fischbestimmer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/fischbestimmer/</guid><description>This is an experiment of porting the FISHIDENTIFIER from the Deutsches Meeresmuseeum Stralsund to LiaScript. The original version can be found at:
https://www.ostsee-fischbestimmer.de/en/bestimmer
This port was done on the basis of the German version, but it was possible to translate the entire functionality into LiaScript.
Visit the Fischbestimmer Usage
About 80 species of fish regularly occur in the Baltic Sea. Roughly the same amount of species occasionally enters as vagrants from the the North Sea or via discharging rivers.</description></item><item><title>How To Code in Python 3</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/how-to-code-in-python-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/how-to-code-in-python-3/</guid><description>This is a port of DigitalOcean’s How To Code in Python 3 tutorial series by Lisa Tagliaferri translated to LiaScript with interactive PyScript examples.
Start Course This example uses the PyScript template which implements some basic macros for integrating the PyScript into LiaScript and to make Markdown code-blocks executable.
The GitHub repository for this project can be found here:
https://github.com/LiaBooks/How-To-Code-in-Python-3
&amp;hellip; or try it out in the LiveEditor:</description></item><item><title>Arbeitsbuch PROLOG (German)</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/arbeitsbuch-prolog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/arbeitsbuch-prolog/</guid><description>Dieses Buch soll in die Programmiersprache PROLOG und in die mit ihr verbundene &amp;lsquo;Logik-programmierung&amp;rsquo; einführen. Die Idee, &amp;lsquo;Logik als eine Programmiersprache&amp;rsquo; zu verwenden, führt zu einer völlig neuen Auffassung vom Programmieren: Das Programm ist nicht eine Folge von Handlungsanweisungen, sondern eine Sammlung von Fakten und Regeln. Das zu lösende Problem wird als eine Anfrage an diese Sammlung formuliert. Im Idealfall führt die logisch korrekte Formulierung der Regeln und der Anfrage zur Lösung des Problems.</description></item><item><title>C-Programmierung (German)</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/c-programmierung/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/c-programmierung/</guid><description>Dies ist eine interaktive Portierung des freien Wikibuches C-Programmierung nach LiaScript.
Um die Beispielprogramme in diesem Buch ausführbar zu gestalten, wird auf die kostenlose und nicht kommerzielle API von CodeRunner zurückgegriffen. Dieser wird unter einer kostenlosen Heroku-Instanz gehostet, sodass das aufwecken des Servers manchmal bis zu 30 Sekunden in Anspruch nehmen kann. Dann sollte es flüssig laufen ;-)
Kurs Starten Das GitHub-Repositorium für dieses Projekt befindet sich hier:
https://github.com/LiaBooks/C-Programmierung
&amp;hellip; oder schauen sie sich das Beispiel im LiveEditor an:</description></item><item><title>C-Programming</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/c-programming/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/c-programming/</guid><description>This LiaScript book is based on the free Wikibook on C-Programming. It provides a comprehensive look at the C programming language and its features. Examples are made interactive by using the CodeRunner.
Start Course The GitHub repository for this project can be found here:
https://github.com/LiaBooks/C-Programming
&amp;hellip; or try it out in the LiveEditor:</description></item><item><title>Sister Fox and the Gray Wolf</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/sister-fox-and-the-gray-wolf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/sister-fox-and-the-gray-wolf/</guid><description>These are two early translations of Russian folk take &amp;ldquo;sister fox and the gray wolf&amp;rdquo;. It is a recording of a LiaScript document, see the original versions at: https://github.com/LiaBooks/SisterFoxAndTheGrayWolf
If you try out one of the examples below, make sure that you enable the audio output of your browser, since the text-to-speech is turned of by default.
Original (Russian) Version View on LiaScript
German Version View on LiaScript
Editing Try this out by yourself in the LiveEditor:</description></item></channel></rss>