<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tools on LiaScript</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/tags/tools/</link><description>Recent content in Tools on LiaScript</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://LiaScript.github.io/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting up Atom (Deprecated)</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/setting-up-atom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/setting-up-atom/</guid><description>This post will help you to set up your Atom with the appropriate plugins to speed up your development process. If you have not installed Atom so far, check out our blog-post on Install Atom with LiaScript. It will guide you through the installation procedure for Atom and the two LiaScript plugins and tell you something about the navigation within a document. However, there exist a couple of other plugins for Atom that are very handy and simplify the writing process for Markdown and of course LiaScript</description></item><item><title>Install Atom with LiaScript (Deprecated)</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/install-atom-with-liascript/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/install-atom-with-liascript/</guid><description>This blog entry presents a little workaround and shows how you can still use our two plugins to develop your LiaScript courses offline with the Atom editor. Unfortunately, it is not possible for us at the moment to update the LiaScript packages for Atom, we hope this problem will be solved soon. On the other hand, it is now also possible to use Visual Studio Code.
Download and install git from: https://git-scm.</description></item><item><title>Install Visual Studio Code with LiaScript</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/install-visual-studio-code-with-liascript/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/install-visual-studio-code-with-liascript/</guid><description>Due to some problems with package updates for Atom editor, we decided to created two LiaScript extensions for VSCode.
However, Atom can still be used to create LiaScript courses and from our point of view it is still the easier editor to learn (for more information follow this link). But, it is now also possible to develop courses and preview them with Visual-Studio-Code. The two extensions are similar to those we had developed for Atom, but with slight differences.</description></item></channel></rss>