<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Testimonials on LiaScript</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/tags/testimonials/</link><description>Recent content in Testimonials on LiaScript</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://LiaScript.github.io/tags/testimonials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Offene Bildungsmaterialien an Hochschulen verankern</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/offene-bildungsmaterialien-an-hochschulen-verankern/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/offene-bildungsmaterialien-an-hochschulen-verankern/</guid><description>Die Förderung von Open Educational Resources (OER) an Hochschulen gewinnt durch die Entwicklung und Implementierung spezifischer OER-Policies an Struktur und Sichtbarkeit. Hierfür wurde ein OER Policy Kit mithilfe von LiaScript entwickelt und veröffentlicht. Dieser Handlungsleitfaden bietet neben einer allgemeinen Orientierung auch konkrete Tipps, Beispiele und hilfreiche Ansätze. Interessierte können das OER Policy Kit direkt online einsehen und sich tiefergehend mit den Materialien auseinandersetzen.
Link zum OER Policy Kit Oder über das offene Git-Repository einsehen, nachnutzen und mitentwickeln:</description></item><item><title>Podcast: Data Management Training at the University of Vienna</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/data-management-training-ag-the-university-of-vienna/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/data-management-training-ag-the-university-of-vienna/</guid><description>This podcast delves into the University of Vienna&amp;rsquo;s innovative data management training program, developed by a diverse team of data stewards for a wide audience including PhD students and technical staff. It emphasizes the importance of general data management skills and specialized knowledge for specific infrastructures, alongside their methodical evaluation of the program&amp;rsquo;s impact. The project aims to support researchers with data management and promote FAIR data practices, driven by their personal interests ranging from web preservation to facilitating custom solutions for scientific inquiries.</description></item></channel></rss>