<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Languages on LiaScript</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/tags/languages/</link><description>Recent content in Languages on LiaScript</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://LiaScript.github.io/tags/languages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Multimedia Comments in LiaScript - This Changes Everything</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/multimedia-comments-in-liascript-this-changes-everything/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/multimedia-comments-in-liascript-this-changes-everything/</guid><description>How can you add your voice or short video sequences to your LiaScript courses? With the new multimedia comments feature, it’s now possible. This feature allows you to replay your voice or video directly in the browser as part of a LiaScript course. It&amp;rsquo;s a game changer for educators looking to create interactive and engaging courses.
How Does It Look? It’s quite straightforward. Simply add a multimedia link using LiaScript syntax to the beginning or end of your comment.</description></item><item><title>Digital Fellows im Spotlight: OER als Grundlage für und Ergebnis von digital gestützter Lehrpraxis</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/digital-fellows-im-spotlight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/digital-fellows-im-spotlight/</guid><description>Das Digital Fellows Programm in Sachsen fördert die Entwicklung und Umsetzung digitaler Lehr- und Lernkonzepte an Hochschulen. Teilnehmende, bekannt als Fellows, implementieren innovative Projekte in verschiedenen Fachbereichen, um die digitale Bildung zu stärken. Sie arbeiten an Themen wie der Verbesserung von Lehrkompetenzen mittels Technologie, der Entwicklung von multimedialen Lernmodulen und der Förderung digitaler Kompetenzen. Ziel ist es, flexible Lernprozesse zu unterstützen und die Hochschullehre durch den Einsatz digitaler Tools zu bereichern.</description></item><item><title>Fonts: Dead or Alive</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/fonts-dead-or-alive/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/fonts-dead-or-alive/</guid><description>Fascinated by the length of the URL as well as by foreign languages and writing systems we added the opportunity to use different fonts in LiaScript-Markdown. We hoped that this can be useful for learning ancient and extinct languages&amp;hellip;
Not all fonts are installed on my machine, so they are not displayed in the editor. LiaScript however will load and display them appropriately. Since they are Unicode-characters, you can style and use these ancient writing systems as ordinary Markdown.</description></item><item><title>One Document - Multiple Representations</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/one-document-mutliple-representations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/one-document-mutliple-representations/</guid><description>This is part one of a demo series that explains certain LiaScript design elements. I this part you will learn how to create narrative presentations from one Markdown document only and how one course can be used to teach in different languages. For the text to speech output we apply simple-speech &amp;hellip;
If your browser does not support TTS, LiaScript will fallback ResponsiveVoice.
You can use this this example as a basis for your own course by following this link</description></item></channel></rss>