<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Article on LiaScript</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/categories/article/</link><description>Recent content in Article on LiaScript</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://LiaScript.github.io/categories/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Open Education Needs a Common Language!?</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/why-open-education-needs-a-common-language/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/why-open-education-needs-a-common-language/</guid><description>A better question would be: Why do commercial offerings and e-learning platforms dominate online education and &amp;ldquo;NOT&amp;rdquo; Open Educational Resources (OER)?
Before we attempt to answer these questions, we want everyone to complete the following sentence for themselves:
Open Educational Resources (OER) are primarily about &amp;hellip;
&amp;hellip; the use of content. &amp;hellip; their creation. It is no wonder that many initially think of licenses and terms of use. Creation (2.) seems boring and time-consuming.</description></item><item><title>Creating interactive Diagrams with eCharts</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/creating-interactive-diagrams-with-echarts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/creating-interactive-diagrams-with-echarts/</guid><description>LiaScript uses the powerful eCharts library to create interactive diagrams, whether you&amp;rsquo;re visualizing ASCII art or presenting data from tables. In our previous blog post, we introduced the &amp;lt;lia-chart&amp;gt; tag—a custom web component that uses eCharts under the hood to easily generate custom diagrams.
Creating interactive Diagrams with ChatGPT Exploring AI-generated content opens the door to fascinating possibilities. In this article, we delve into how you can leverage AI models, like ChatGPT, to create interactive diagrams that can be customized on the fly.</description></item><item><title>Teach Your AI to Generate LiaScript Previews</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/teach-your-ai-to-generate-liascript-previews/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/teach-your-ai-to-generate-liascript-previews/</guid><description>Claude.ai offers a powerful feature in its paid version that allows you to preview generated code directly. However, with a simple prompt, you can teach any AI to create LiaScript previews on demand—even if you’re using a free version.
What Are Data-URIs? In a previous post, we briefly covered how you can use data-URIs to encode LiaScript content.
Where is Content Stored? Did you know that LiaScript tries to be agnostic as possible, when it comes to hosting?</description></item><item><title>Creating interactive Diagrams with ChatGPT</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/creating-interactive-diagrams-with-chatgpt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/creating-interactive-diagrams-with-chatgpt/</guid><description>Exploring AI-generated content opens the door to fascinating possibilities. In this article, we delve into how you can leverage AI models, like ChatGPT, to create interactive diagrams that can be customized on the fly.
Prompt with Variables and Examples While ChatGPT might not be capable of independently generating complex scripts, it excels at modifying existing code snippets to meet your needs. Take, for example, a script from the LiaScript documentation, specifically from the section on Custom Diagrams with ECharts.</description></item><item><title>Changing Layout - FlexBox is your Friend</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/changing-layout-flexbox-is-your-friend/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/changing-layout-flexbox-is-your-friend/</guid><description>In this article, we will show you how to change the layout of certain parts of your LiaScript course easily with FlexBox. FlexBox is a powerful layout tool that allows you to create complex layouts with minimal code. It is supported by all modern browsers and is easy to use.
What is FlexBox? FlexBox, or the Flexible Box Layout Module, is a CSS layout model that provides a more efficient way to design complex layouts without relying heavily on float or positioning.</description></item><item><title>Collaborative drawings made with LiaScript</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/collaborative-drawings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/collaborative-drawings/</guid><description>In this article we will explore how to create a collaborative drawing canvas (in other words a whiteboard) using LiaScript&amp;rsquo;s internal publish -subscribe mechanisms. This feature will allows multiple users to interact with the same LiaScript course in real-time, enabling collaborative drawing and marking, as demonstrated in the following video.
1. Publish-Subscribe (How does it work?) The publish-subscribe (pub-sub) pattern is a messaging paradigm where messages are sent by publishers to specific topics without the publisher knowing who, if anyone, will receive the message.</description></item><item><title>Multimedia Comments in LiaScript - This Changes Everything</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/multimedia-comments-in-liascript-this-changes-everything/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/multimedia-comments-in-liascript-this-changes-everything/</guid><description>How can you add your voice or short video sequences to your LiaScript courses? With the new multimedia comments feature, it’s now possible. This feature allows you to replay your voice or video directly in the browser as part of a LiaScript course. It&amp;rsquo;s a game changer for educators looking to create interactive and engaging courses.
How Does It Look? It’s quite straightforward. Simply add a multimedia link using LiaScript syntax to the beginning or end of your comment.</description></item><item><title>ChatGPT als OER Koautor - ein interaktiver Kurs in 10 Minuten (German)</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/chatgpt-als-koautor-ein-interaktiver-kurs-in10-minute/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/chatgpt-als-koautor-ein-interaktiver-kurs-in10-minute/</guid><description>Wie nutzt man ChatGPT um interaktive Kurse für LiaScript zu erstellen, wird in diesem Video gezeigt&amp;hellip; Manchmal muss man bei den Kursen noch manuell nacharbeiten aber gefühlt wird ChatGPT immer besser&amp;hellip;
Prompt Verändert und experimentiert mit dem folgenden Prompt, um eure eigenen interaktiven Kurse zu erstellen:
Generiere einen interaktiven Kurs zum Thema &amp;#34;Schnittpunkt von zwei Geraden&amp;#34; für Schüler der 7. Klasse als LiaScript Code: 1. Beschreibe das Lernziel, 2. erläutere die unterschiedlichen Fälle der Lage von zwei Geraden, 3.</description></item><item><title>Open Textbook Repositories</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/open-textbook-repositories/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/open-textbook-repositories/</guid><description>This alphabetically sorted overview is fare from being complete, but it should give you a good starting point to find open textbooks for your courses. If you want to collaborate with us in order to translate such books into LiaScript, have a look at the following blog-post.
What Do Poland and Arnold Schwarzenegger Have in Common? &amp;hellip; for translating open textbooks into interactive LiaScript books. But, based on our discussions at the eLearning Africa Conference we realized that there is a need for open textbooks for various purposes.</description></item><item><title>Sharing Content via WebTorrent</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/sharing-content-via-webtorrent/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/sharing-content-via-webtorrent/</guid><description>This demo from the eLearning-Africa Conference 2024, shows how to use WebTorrent to share educational content with LiaScript. Everything that you need is a modern browser, no additional software, no login or authentication is required.
But what is WebTorrent and how can it be used in an educational context? This article provides an overview of WebTorrent, its benefits, and practical applications for educators.
Understanding WebTorrent: A Guide for Educators In today&amp;rsquo;s digital age, sharing and accessing educational content efficiently is crucial for educators and students alike.</description></item><item><title>What Do Poland and Arnold Schwarzenegger Have in Common?</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/what-do-poland-and-arnold-schwarzenegger-have-in-common/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/what-do-poland-and-arnold-schwarzenegger-have-in-common/</guid><description>&amp;hellip; for translating open textbooks into interactive LiaScript books. But, based on our discussions at the eLearning Africa Conference we realized that there is a need for open textbooks for various purposes. With the LiaBooks project we would like to translate such open textbooks from around the world into LiaScript. This way, we hope to make digital textbooks more accessible, reusable and adaptable for everyone. If you are interested in this project, please feel free to contact us and help us to translate such books into a more interactive format.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Community Projects on GitHub versus Traditional Publishing Models for OER</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/open-source-community-projects-on-github-versus-traditional-publishing-models-for-oer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/open-source-community-projects-on-github-versus-traditional-publishing-models-for-oer/</guid><description>In this post, I will aim to make a case for Git and GitHub by comparing how &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; publishing models (for OER) can be improved through dynamic, flexible, and transparent open-source community projects. So, what can OER learn from open source and how can it be applied? GitHub promotes collaborative development and the global exchange of educational materials, supported by powerful tools like Git. The platform enables broad quality control through open review processes and facilitates the organization and management of educational projects through specific organizations.</description></item><item><title>LiaScript - WorldMap</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/liascript-world-map/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/liascript-world-map/</guid><description>This idea was motivated by the OER-World Map in order to to visualize the distribution of educational content that was created with LiaScript or events and meetings. Our map is based on the OpenStreetMap and uses the Leaflet library to display the markers. Blue is associated to projects, while future events are displayed in green and past events in transparent gray.
visit the world-map All information about the projects is stored within a static YAML-file:</description></item><item><title>LiaScript 0.14 - Full Documentation (English)</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/liascript-documentation-english/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/liascript-documentation-english/</guid><description>This is a screencast of the LiaScript documentation in presentation mode spoken by LiaScript itself ;-)
You can inspect the document by your own, either directly from GitHub or as the interactive LiaScript version.
0. Intro 1. Overview on Tools &amp;amp; More Update:
You can now also use VS-Code as your editor, there are now two additional extensions within the marketplace, one for previews and one for snippets.
Check out the following link for more information.</description></item><item><title>LiaScript 0.14 - Partial Documentation (Korean)</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/liascript-documentation-korean/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/liascript-documentation-korean/</guid><description>This is an automated translation of the LiaScript LiaScript into the Korean language.
You can inspect the document by your own, either directly from GitHub or as the interactive LiaScript version.
1. Overview on Tools &amp;amp; More Update:
You can now also use VS-Code as your editor, there are now two additional extensions within the marketplace, one for previews and one for snippets.
Check out the following link for more information.</description></item><item><title>LiaScript 0.14 - Partial Documentation (Ukrainian)</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/liascript-documentation-ukrainian/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/liascript-documentation-ukrainian/</guid><description>This is an automated translation of the LiaScript LiaScript into the Ukrainian language.
You can inspect the document by your own, either directly from GitHub or as the interactive LiaScript version.
1. Overview on Tools &amp;amp; More Update:
You can now also use VS-Code as your editor, there are now two additional extensions within the marketplace, one for previews and one for snippets.
Check out the following link for more information.</description></item><item><title>LiaScript 0.14 - Teilweise Dokumentation (German)</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/liascript-documentation-german/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/liascript-documentation-german/</guid><description>Dies ist die Aufnahme von LiaScript im Präsentationsmodus, indem die Dokumentation sich selber vorstellt.
Es ist natürlich möglich der Dokumentation auch selber im interaktiven LiaScript-Modus zur folgen, klicken sie hier. Die Quellen finden Sie auch direkt auf GitHub.
0. Intro 1. Kurzeinführung Tools &amp;amp; Co. Update:
Es ist jetzt auch möglich VSCode als Editor für LiaScript-Kurse zu nutzen. Dafür haben wir die beiden folgenden Erweiterungen zum VSCode-Marktplatz hinzugefügt (eines für die Vorschau, das andere für Snippets).</description></item><item><title>Offene Bildungsmaterialien auf twillo finden und teilen</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/offene-bildungsmaterialien-auf-twillo-finden-und-teilen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/offene-bildungsmaterialien-auf-twillo-finden-und-teilen/</guid><description>Twillo ist ein Portal, das sich auf offene Bildungsmaterialien (OER) spezialisiert hat, insbesondere im Bereich der Hochschullehre. Es ermöglicht Nutzern, Bildungsmaterialien zu finden, zu teilen und bietet zudem verschiedene Dienstleistungen wie Workshops zu OER, eine OER-Planungshilfe, Vorlagen zur Erstellung von OER und ein Rechtsquiz zur Überprüfung des Wissens über rechtskonforme Lehre. Twillo fördert die Verfügbarkeit, Anpassung, und Vernetzung von OER, um offene Lehr- und Lernkulturen sowie lebenslanges Lernen zu unterstützen.</description></item><item><title>Promoting your Content</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/promoting-your-content/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/promoting-your-content/</guid><description>If you want to &amp;ldquo;promote&amp;rdquo; the LiaScript content you have created, or share it with a wider audience, then you can use the following methods.
0. Add LiaScript meta-information Add a first HTML-comment to your Markdown document, as depicted below. This HTML-comment should provide at least the information about the author, an email address for contacting, a comment that summarizes your course in a few sentences, a logo, and an optional repository, which points to your GitHub, GitLab repository, if the course will be served from somewhere else.</description></item><item><title>Setting up Atom (Deprecated)</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/setting-up-atom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/setting-up-atom/</guid><description>This post will help you to set up your Atom with the appropriate plugins to speed up your development process. If you have not installed Atom so far, check out our blog-post on Install Atom with LiaScript. It will guide you through the installation procedure for Atom and the two LiaScript plugins and tell you something about the navigation within a document. However, there exist a couple of other plugins for Atom that are very handy and simplify the writing process for Markdown and of course LiaScript</description></item><item><title>Install Atom with LiaScript (Deprecated)</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/install-atom-with-liascript/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/install-atom-with-liascript/</guid><description>This blog entry presents a little workaround and shows how you can still use our two plugins to develop your LiaScript courses offline with the Atom editor. Unfortunately, it is not possible for us at the moment to update the LiaScript packages for Atom, we hope this problem will be solved soon. On the other hand, it is now also possible to use Visual Studio Code.
Download and install git from: https://git-scm.</description></item><item><title>Install Visual Studio Code with LiaScript</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/install-visual-studio-code-with-liascript/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/install-visual-studio-code-with-liascript/</guid><description>Due to some problems with package updates for Atom editor, we decided to created two LiaScript extensions for VSCode.
However, Atom can still be used to create LiaScript courses and from our point of view it is still the easier editor to learn (for more information follow this link). But, it is now also possible to develop courses and preview them with Visual-Studio-Code. The two extensions are similar to those we had developed for Atom, but with slight differences.</description></item><item><title>Students work on open learning content</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/students-work-on-open-learning-content/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/students-work-on-open-learning-content/</guid><description>This is a translated version of a German article that was published on april 22 in 2022 here: https://tu-freiberg.de/presse/studierende-arbeiten-an-offenen-lerninhalten-mit
The Institute for Computer Science has developed an interactive type of lecture format. Together with the lecturers, the students work on the lecture materials with open tools via a website - without any PDF documents or PowerPoint slide collections.
Prof. Sebastian Zug during his lecture. Photo: TU Bergakademie Freiberg
With one click, students can display the content in different languages, develop an executable program code or start simulations.</description></item><item><title>Embedding Multimedia - How does it work??</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/embedding-multimedia-how-does-it-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/embedding-multimedia-how-does-it-work/</guid><description>LiaScript has a new type of link. If you prefix a link in Markdown with an exclamation mark, then this link is marked as an image, and it gets embedded into the document. LiaScript had already two extensions for this, the question-mark is used to indicate audio (just think of an ear) and images with sound which are used as markers for video content.
![image](url) ?[audio](url) !?[video](url) One benefit of using this notation is, that this does not interfere with Markdown, the link is still valid and &amp;ldquo;clickable&amp;rdquo; in any other Markdown-viewer.</description></item><item><title>OE³R the next Generation of OER?</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/oe3r/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/oe3r/</guid><description>OER or in long Open Educational Resources is a “relatively” new and vaguely defined term. Wikipedia describes it as follows:
Open educational resources (OER) are freely accessible, openly licensed text, media, and other digital assets that are useful for teaching, learning, and assessing as well as for research purposes&amp;hellip;
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_educational_resources
Thus, the ER defines any kind of Educational¹ content while the O points to an open licensing format. But the idea is actually not new at all, there have been attempts that predate the OER movement by nearly a century.</description></item><item><title>LiaScript Cheet-Sheet (German)</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/liascript-cheet-sheet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/liascript-cheet-sheet/</guid><description>Ein Spickzettel der wichtgsten LiaScript-Funktionalität. Weitere sind in Vorbereitung &amp;hellip;
Überschriften # Überschrift 1 ## Überschrift 2 ### Überschrift 3 #### Überschrift 4 ##### Überschrift 5 ###### Überschrift 6 Texthervorhebungen _kursiv_ auch *kursig* __fett__ auch __fett__ ___kursiv___ und ***fett*** ~durchgestrichen~ ~~unterstrichen~~ ~~~durch- &amp;amp; unterstrichen~~~ ^hochgestellt^ `unformatierter Code` Textblock Einfache Blöcke/Absätze werden durch Leerzeilen voneinander getrennt und können bel. lang sein. &amp;gt; Blöcke mit einem vorangestellten `&amp;gt;` &amp;gt; werden hervorgeboben dargestellt. Listen Ungeordnet:</description></item><item><title>LiaScript: Crash-courSe in 13 Akten (German)</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/liascript-crash-course-in-13-akten/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/liascript-crash-course-in-13-akten/</guid><description>Dieses Tutorial führt in 13 „kurzen“ Schritt-für-Schritt Videos in die Kursentwicklung mit LiaScript ein, von der Installation des Editors hin zu den wichtigsten Gestaltungsmöglichkeiten. Wie erstellt man interaktive Inhalte, nutzt Animationen und bringt dem Kurs das Sprechen bei&amp;hellip;
Eine Zusammenfassung der wichtigsten Punkte je Video wird gegeben.
#1 Installation Installation des Editors und der benötigten Plugins
Die Quellen sind unten noch einmal aufgelistet, es wird einerseits der Atom-Editor benötigt, sowie die beiden Plugins.</description></item><item><title>From Hero to Zero with Learning Management Systems</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/from-hero-to-zero-with-lms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/from-hero-to-zero-with-lms/</guid><description>Why and How LMSs fail in distributing knowledge Abstract: Learning Management Systems provide more restrictions than access to educational resources and developing courses with the offered authoring tools is more tedious and intimidating task than a creative one. These claims are proved by adopting metrics from software-development, additionally a possible solution is presented: LiaScript is a domain-specific language that is based on Markdown and open-source principles, targeting interactive online-course development.</description></item><item><title>LiaScript: a domain-specific-language for interactive online courses</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/liascript-a-domain-specific-language-for-interactive-online-courses/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/liascript-a-domain-specific-language-for-interactive-online-courses/</guid><description>This is the first paper published about LiaScript, which was presented at the International Association for Development of the Information Society (IADIS) International Conference on e-Learning 2019 in Porto. It gives an overview of the language and its features, as well as the motivation behind its development.
Abstract. LiaScript is an attempt to enable everyone to create free and interactive online courses, without the need of being an experienced programmer. Instead, it aims to bring both parties, software-and course-developers, closer together by introducing Open-Source techniques into the Open-courSe development process.</description></item></channel></rss>