<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>JavaScript on LiaScript</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/tags/javascript/</link><description>Recent content in JavaScript on LiaScript</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://LiaScript.github.io/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>JavaScript and Image-Filtering</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/javascript-and-image-filtering/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/javascript-and-image-filtering/</guid><description>The following short example shows how script tags can be applyed to images in order to create a simple image-filtering effect. In LiaScript, the script tag is a reimagined version of a JavaScript-component that has a lifetime, can be combined with input-tags and has an output as well. Additionally, scripts can be stiched together by an execution graph, which is defined by the output of the script-tags. The script is executed in the browser and can be used to manipulate the image in real-time.</description></item><item><title>Importing a local WebCam-stream into a Presentation</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/importing-a-local-camera-stream-into-a-presentation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/importing-a-local-camera-stream-into-a-presentation/</guid><description>Sometimes you want to show a live video stream from a local WebCam in your presentation, without having to move to another application. This can be done with the following script and video-tag. It will ask for permission to access the camera and will display the video stream in a video element. If you click on the button again, the camera will be closed.
Simply copy both tags into your LiaScript document and you will be able to open and close the camera stream with the button.</description></item></channel></rss>