<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MOOC on LiaScript</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/tags/mooc/</link><description>Recent content in MOOC on LiaScript</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://LiaScript.github.io/tags/mooc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Open Education Needs a Common Language!?</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/why-open-education-needs-a-common-language/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/why-open-education-needs-a-common-language/</guid><description>A better question would be: Why do commercial offerings and e-learning platforms dominate online education and &amp;ldquo;NOT&amp;rdquo; Open Educational Resources (OER)?
Before we attempt to answer these questions, we want everyone to complete the following sentence for themselves:
Open Educational Resources (OER) are primarily about &amp;hellip;
&amp;hellip; the use of content. &amp;hellip; their creation. It is no wonder that many initially think of licenses and terms of use. Creation (2.) seems boring and time-consuming.</description></item><item><title>Data and Analytics for Research Training (DART)</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/data-and-analytics-for-research-training/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/data-and-analytics-for-research-training/</guid><description>The DART program offers free, open-source educational resources aimed at empowering working biomedical researchers with data science skills to enhance their work. It aligns with the National Institutes of Health&amp;rsquo;s focus on boosting research reproducibility, transparency, and rigor through instructional modules that teach data science and related abilities. The program adopts a modular educational strategy, allowing learners to tailor their training by choosing from various modules to create a personalized learning pathway.</description></item><item><title>From Hero to Zero with Learning Management Systems</title><link>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/from-hero-to-zero-with-lms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://LiaScript.github.io/blog/from-hero-to-zero-with-lms/</guid><description>Why and How LMSs fail in distributing knowledge Abstract: Learning Management Systems provide more restrictions than access to educational resources and developing courses with the offered authoring tools is more tedious and intimidating task than a creative one. These claims are proved by adopting metrics from software-development, additionally a possible solution is presented: LiaScript is a domain-specific language that is based on Markdown and open-source principles, targeting interactive online-course development.</description></item></channel></rss>